<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/hugo-slum/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hugo-slum/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4. Deploying a site</title>
      <link>/hugo-slum/post/deploying-a-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hugo-slum/post/deploying-a-site/</guid>
      <description>The usual advice with blogdown is to deploy to netlify because it makes a few things easier than doing it with GitHub pages. Naturally, I just have to do things the hard way…
The .nojekyll file is neededThe baseurl in the config.toml file is neededManaging the tension between public and docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3. Customising a post</title>
      <link>/hugo-slum/post/customising-a-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hugo-slum/post/customising-a-post/</guid>
      <description>Here is some text that I have written. This page uses the light theme. To make life a little easier I’ve also written a small package that supplies ggplot2 themes that are consistent with the slum styles:
#devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;djnavarro/slumstyle&amp;quot;)library(slumstyle)library(tidyverse)The background colour for this theme is very slightly grey rather than white, so if you want a plot to blend in with the background you need to do something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2. Writing a post</title>
      <link>/hugo-slum/post/writing-a-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hugo-slum/post/writing-a-post/</guid>
      <description>The slum provides a simple Hugo theme intended primarily to be used in conjunction with the blogdown package, so posts take the form of R Markdown documents rather than plain markdown. I’m fairly certain that the theme supports plain markdown, but given that the appeal of blogdown lies in integrating R Markdown with the Hugo blogging system I’ll jump straight to it.
1. The YAML headerLike any R Markdown document, a post begins with the YAML header.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1. Getting started</title>
      <link>/hugo-slum/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hugo-slum/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>My initial goal in writing the slum theme was purely selfish: I use blogdown on my own blog and I wanted to understand how it works. To help me learn, I decided to read the documentation and tinker with the minimalistic XMin theme. I… um… got a little carried away, and ended up with a fairly flexible blogging template with a few more bells and whistles than I was expecting. I wasn’t entirely convinced it would be useful, so I named it Somewhat-Light Unhelpfully-Minimal Hugo theme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>